MVC is a software architecture - the structure of the system - that separates business  logic from the rest of the user interface . 
It does this by separating the application into three parts: the model, the view, and the controller to improve maintainability.

The model manages all the operations related to behaviors data. It can respond to requests for information and respond to instructions to change the state of its information.
This could be a database, or any number of data structures or storage systems.

The view effectively provides the user interface element of the application. It'll render data from the model into a form that is suitable for the user interface.

The controller takes in user commands, sends commands to the model for data updates, sends instructions to view to update interface.

All in all, these three components work together to create the three basic components of MVC.

 Benefits of MVC 
● Reduce Code Complexity
● Improve maintainability
● Code Reuse – Well factored code lends itself to reuse 
● Increased Flexibility 
● Decoupled Code – Fewer depedencies
● Test driven development is possible